Guide to the Records of the Office of the Treasurer (Muriel L. Mantel) RG.10
New York University Archives
- Series II: Washington Square
  - Waverly Place Building (24-26 Waverly leases), 1944-1951 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - 24-26 Waverly Place Hall of Residence, 1937-1947 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - 25 Waverly Institute of Mathematical Sciences (1 of 3), 1953-1955 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - 25 Waverly Institute of Mathematical Sciences (2 of 3), 1952-1953 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - 25 Waverly Institute of Mathematical Sciences (3 of 3), 1953-1954 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - 28-30 Waverly Place (1 of 2), 1937-1947 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - 28-30 Waverly Place (2 of 2), 1937-1939 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Waverly Place Entrance from School of Law to Wash. Square College, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - 32 Waverly Place - John Lowry Jr. Correspondence, 1921-1923 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - 32 Waverly Place, 1911-1926 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Project with Webb Institute, 1939-1942 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Waverly Place Conduit, 14 feet west of Greene St, 1959-1966 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - West Broadway Pipelines, 1957-1958 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - 35-37-39 West Fourth Street (1 of 2), 1917-1928 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - 35-37-39 West Fourth Street (2 of 2), 1928-1929 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - 48-50 West 4th Street, 1926 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - Eighth Street, 1952-1953 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Widening of First Ave, 1940 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Widening of Waverly Place, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Women's Faculty Club - Dean of Women, 1922-1923, 1946-1953 (Box 53, Folder 13)
- Series III: University Heights
  - Aeronautics Fund, 1923-1927 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Aeronautics, Guggenheim School of (College of Engineering), 1950-1959 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Aeronautics, Daniel Guggenheim School of, 1940-1955 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Airport, Proposed New York University, 1926 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Gymnasium, 1945-1950 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Alterations, University Heights, 1946-1947 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Andrews Avenue Properties, 1956-1968 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Armory, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Army Housing (1 of 2), 1943-1955 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Army Housing (2 of 2), 1943 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - University Heights Blueprints, 1912-1914, 1931-1955 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Campus Concert Course, 1919-1920 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Cannon - Battery Hill, 1942-1948 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Cedar Avenue Properties, 1967-1968 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Central Business Office, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Operation and Maintenance, 1924-1932, 1947-1950 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Consolidated Edison & Labberton Reports (1 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Consolidated Edison & Labberton Reports (2 of 2), 1948-1954 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Consolidated Edison Company Re: Diesel Unit Generators, 1943 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Consolidated Edison Company: Transfer of Gas Services and Mains to NYU, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Consolidated Shipbuilding Corp.(1 of 2), 1947-1951 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Consolidated Shipbuilding Corp.(2 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Consolidated Telegraph & Electrical Subway Company - Agreement with, 1917, 1943-1952 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Consolidated Telegraph & Electrical Subway Company - Duct Line, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Conversion from Coal to Oil/Smoke Abatement, 1947-1948 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1926-1936 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Day and Klauder, 1916-1923 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Dupont Fellowship Agreement, 1939-1940 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - 9/11 East 37th Street/Institute of Fine Arts, 1927-1938 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Engineering Building Alterations, 1947-1951 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Engineering Center, 1956-1958 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Proposed Engineering Building Alterations, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Proposed Engineering Building - Con Ed, 1934-1950 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Engineering, College of - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1941-1945 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Engineering, College of - Defalcation of John H. McBride, 1949-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Engineering, College of - Defense Training Program, 1940-1945 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Engineering, College of - Expired Agreements Engineering Research, 1943 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Engineering, College of - Government Billing and Reserves, 1949-1952 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Engineering, College of - Institute of Technology, Proposed, 1946-1947 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Engineering, College of - Nichols Engineering and Research Corporation Research Fellowship, 1938 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Engineering College Research Council, 1955-1957 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Engineering, College of - Research Division, 1950-1962 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Engineering, College of - "Research Era" Proposal to Dr. Work, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Research Lab, 1920-1922 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Financial Report: College of Arts and Pure Science, College of Engineering, Dormitory Rents, 1920-1921 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Financial Report: College of Arts and Pure Science, College of Engineering, Dormitory Rents, 1922-1923 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Financial Report: College of Arts and Pure Science, College of Engineering, Dormitory Rents, 1923-1924 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Goldman Band Concerts, 1925-1937 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Gould Hall of Technology (Tech I), 1956-1970 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Gould Student Center, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Government Funded Dormitory, 1950-1953 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Government Financed Dormitory Project, 1953-1953 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Fire Prevention Laboratory, 1928 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Government Financed Dormitory, 1954-1956 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Greater New York Outdoor Art Exhibit, 1953-1955 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Housing - Emergency War Courses, 1942, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Joint Planning Committee, 1947-1950 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Loew Dormitories, 1953-1973 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - 2186 Loring Place + 135 Hall of Fame Terrace, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Loring Place Properties, 1956-1968 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - MacCracken Plot, 1960-1961 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Maps and Pictures, 1937-1952 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Military Custodian for ROTC and AROTC, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Military Science Building and Guggenheim Science Center, 1940-1941 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Administrative Material, 1919-1936, 1955-1962 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - New York Central Railroad - Easement Railroad Tracks, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - New York Central Railroad Footbridge, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - William H. Nichols Chemistry Building, 1925-1927 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - William H. Nichols Chemistry Building, 1927-1975 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Nichols Hall Building, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Ohio Field, 1946-1955 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Onderdonk Service Building, 1961 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Organ, 1932 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Parking Garage, 1964-1968 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Phi Gamma Delta, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Physics Buildings - Planning Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Planning (Power Plant/Armory), 1952-1953 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Plant Committee, 1948-1952 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Power Plant, 1933 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Power Plant, 1934 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Power Plant, 1935-1936 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Power Plant, 1934-1948 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Power Plant, 1938-1941 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Steam and Generating Plant, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Retaining Wall of Presbyterian Church, undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Properties, 1940s-1950s (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Properties, 1939-1950 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Property Acquisitions, 1961-1969 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Property, Assistant Supervisor of University Heights, undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Residence Hall #1 1980 Sedgwick Ave., 1907-1948 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Residence Hall #3 2079 Wiegand Place, 1914-1942 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Residence Hall # 4 2081 Wiegand Place, 1923-1946 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Residence Hall #5 2084 Wiegand Place, 1924-1931 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Residence Hall #6 206 West 180th Street, 1922-1945 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Research Building #1, 1961-1963 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Research Building #3, 1952-1957 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Sanitary Laboratory, 1935-1967 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Sedgwick Ave Property purchased from Delta Sigma Phi, 1929 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Sedgwick Ave Properties, 1956-1967 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Proposed Projects 34 Sedgwick Avenue, 1919-1921 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Site Development Plan, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - South Hall, 1924-1948 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Student Center (Lawrence House), 1935-1936 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Student Union, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Summer School, 1906-1910 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Summer School, 1910-1914 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Summer School, 1914-1919 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Summer School, 1919-1922 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Summer School, 1922-1923 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Taxes Exemption for Cyrus C. Miller, 1943 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Technical Tape Corporation Agreement (Res. Bldg. No. 1), undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Technology Building, 1955-1958 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Technology Building II, 1965-1973 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Service and Temporary Classroom Building, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - 2015 University Avenue, 1950-1951 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 2015 University Avenue, 1923-1924 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 2015 University Avenue, 1927-1933 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - 2015 University Avenue, 1924-1927 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Richard W. Ulbrich Housing Fraternity, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Veterans Housing Riverside Campus Nursery School, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Property Veterans' and Emergency Housing, undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Water Bills, undated (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - 2078 Weigand Place, 1939-1948 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Weigand Place, 1949-1952 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - West 179th Street Properties, 1961-1969 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - West 180th Street Properties, 1961-1968 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - West 183rd Street Properties, 1965-1973 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Proposal for Construction of Transonic and Supersonic Wind Tunnel Facilities, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Wind Tunnel, undated (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - University Heights YMCA Hut, 1920-1931 (Box 64, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Medical Center
  - Medical Center Properties, 1937-1946 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Medical School - Property Development, 1942-1945 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity "Mission of a Medical School", 1944-1945 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity "Medicine's Tomorrow", 1945-1946 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity "An Investment for Business", 1946 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Medical Center - Idea of Establishing a Medical Group, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity - Mills Sturtevant Memorial Clinic, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity - Women's Committee of NYU - Bellevue Medical Center, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Medical Center Campaign Publicity "A History of Growth", 1948 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Bellevue Medical Center Salaries, 1950-1951 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Agreements and Indenture Between NYU and New York City re: Medical School Properties, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Assets and Liabilities, 1951-1954 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Naming of Tisch Hospital - Medical Center, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Preliminary Joint Meeting - Finance Committee and Steering Committee - April 10, 1946 and May 1, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum of Intentions, undated (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Federal and State Laws, undated (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Edwin A. Salmon Personal History and Record, undated (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Preliminary Sub-Committee Meeting of the University Council on Medicine - April 21, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Organization, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Administration Sub-Committee of the University Council Committee on Medicine and Dentistry, undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary Meeting of the Finance Committee and Steering Committee - May 1, 1946 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Institute of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, undated (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Organization and Sub-Committee, undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Administration Top Organization, undated (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Mergers: NY Post-Graduate Medical School and Hospital into NYU, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Mergers: Stuyvesant Sq. Hospital, Formerly NY Skin and Cancer Hospital into NYU, undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Certificate of Merger, undated (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Booklets of Pictures and Maps, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Negotiations for the Merger with Medical Center and for NYU Post-Graduate Medical School (1 of 2), undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Negotiations for the Merger with Medical Center and for NYU Post-Graduate Medical School (2 of 2), undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Stuyvesant Sq. Hospital, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Stuyvesant Sq. Hospital Certificate of Merger and Consolidation Agreement of Merger and Consolidation Nov. 30, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Sale of Property to City of New York 430-444 1st Ave., 401-421 E. 25th St., 408-414 E. 26th St. May 1, 1945 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Indenture and Agreement in Connection with the Proposed Street Closing and Exchange of Properties, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Property and Land Acquisition - East Side of First Ave. Between Bellevue Hospital and 34th St., 1945-1947 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum Regarding Organization of NYU-Bellevue Medical Center, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Proposed John Doe Institute of Hygiene, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Reorganization of the College of Medicine Clinic, 1946 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Bellevue Nurses Training School Center, 1944-1950 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - College of Medicine Stairway, 1945 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Study of Nursing Education in University, 1949 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Survey and Tentative Plan of Development for University and Bellevue Hospital Medical College, 1930 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Bellevue Training School for Nurses, 1943-1948 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - College of Medicine, Commercial Gifts, 1939-1946 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - College of Medicine, Gifts for Immediate Use, 1934-1939 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Department of Hospitals, East 25th Street Property, 1937-1962 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - District Health and Training Center, 1935-1936 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - District Health and Training Center, 1937-1939 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Fire in Carnegie Laboratory, 1940 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled, 1942 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Irvington House, 1945 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Medical College Center / Adjacent Investment Property, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - College of Medicine Research After 1945, 1945-1947 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1912-1914 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1915-1918 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1918-1921 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - New York Graduate Medical School and Hospital Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - New York Graduate Medical School and Hospital Reports, 1946-1948 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Taxes, 1942 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center Campaign Fund Committee, 1946 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Balance Due on Pledges - NYU-Bellevue Medical Center, 1949 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center Property, 1941-1945 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center Property, 1946 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Project with the Switzer Foundation, 1930-1931 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Legal Cases Involving the School of Medicine, 1926-1945 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Proposed Affiliation with Doctor's Hospital, 1942 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Proposed College of Medicine Building, 1927-1935 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property "Hall of Residence Fund Raising Acknowledgements", undated (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property "Maps and Pictures Relating to the Medical Center", undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property "Medical Center Fund Raising Campaign", undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property School of Medicine Fund Raising (1 of 2), undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property School of Medicine Fund Raising (2 of 2), undated (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Office of Finance Office of the Treasurer - Washington Square Property "Miscellaneous Correspondence - School of Medicine", undated (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Bellevue Medical Center Property, 1947-1951 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1949, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - NYU-Bellevue Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1950-1954 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - NYU-Bellevue Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1955-1958 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Endowment Income - Medical School Budget, 1960-1961 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Reports and Accounts on Medical School and Hospital, 1948-1949 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center Property Layouts and Blueprints, 1918-1945 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center Miscellaneous, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center, 1950-1974 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center Campaign Funds, 1945-1955 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Medical Center - Winthrop Rockefeller Material, 1946-1951 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center Progress Report, 1947-1948 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Veterinary College, 1904-1918 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Veterinary College, 1918-1924 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Veterinary College Funds, 1917-1923 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Veterinary College State Aid, 1920-1921 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - College of Dentistry, 1944 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - College of Dentistry John Doe Institute of Oral Hygiene, 1935-1944 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Dental College Lunchroom, 1937-1939 (Box 74, Folder 7)